Brad W. Duderstadt

Sr. Software Engineer

Location: Kansas City, Missouri 64155 Phone: 816.214.0086

E-mail: brad.duderstadt@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/bradduderstadt

Summary

Impressive career reflects successful experience in multiple industries including Automotive, Marketing, Transportation, and Healthcare IT. Demonstrated history of working closely with product and design teams as well as internal and external facing customers to provide professional technology solutions to solve complex business problems. Highly skilled in System / Web / Software design and Full-Stack development. Extremely creative and possess excellent problem resolutions skills. Exceptional written, verbal and interpersonal communication skills. Strong technology professional that is highly motivated with a passion for learning.

Technologies

JavaScript	React / Hooks	React Native	Node.js	TypeScript	Redux
Web API	REST	CSS/SASS/SCSS	Jenkins	Git/GitHub	Jest
Cypress	PostgreSQL	MySQL	SQL Server	MongoDB	SQL/T-SQL

Experience

Full Stack Engineer (Remote)

Shamrock Trading, Overland Park, KS

April 2021 – Present

- Member of the Internal Apps Audit team building automation tools and services for internal customers utilizing React, Redux, TypeScript, JavaScript, MongoDB and AWS.
- Created new applications and services to facilitate auditors and credit team members to submit, monitor and respond to credit requests with an intuitive UI rather than emails being sent back and forth between teams. The streamlined workflow has resulted in improving throughput by 75% and virtually eliminates communication missteps.
- Built group codes / client update UI and service that allows operations personnel to bulk update
 group codes by dropping a CSV file in the UI rather than having to update them one by one in
 the third-party Cadence application. The application reduced the update process from multiple
 hours to under 30 seconds. A time reduction of 99.5%. The new application has proven to be a
 solid foundation and is now being utilized for all client-based updates.
- Built Invoice Search application (UI and service) this is utilized by the Operations department in the resubmit invoices workflow. By implementing the Invoice Search application into the resubmit invoice workflow the team was able to realize and maintain and 85% time reduction across the workflow.

Software Engineer II (Remote 2020-2021)

VinSolutions, Mission, KS

September 2017 - April 2021

- Key member of the Retail Engagement team building virtual assistant product utilizing React, C#, .NET Core, Web API, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, and AWS.
- Enhanced and maintained domain-specific functionality of enterprise CRM product (Connect CRM) using C#, .NET, React, JavaScript, and jQuery. Refactored logging and error-handling to remove irrelevant logs resulting in an annual savings of \$100,000.

- As part of the Marketing and Engagement maintained and enhanced the enterprise campaign / marketing platform using C#, .NET, Web API, JavaScript and jQuery. Increase throughput of campaigns by 40%.
- Key member of Virtual Assistant tea that designed, built and brough to market the "Vinessa" virtual assistant product for automotive dealers.
- As a member of the CRM / Desking team, refactored the Rates & Residuals functionality making the process flow more fluently and reducing internal API calls by over 50%.

Lead Software Engineer (Remote - Side Gig)

Quinsite, Chapel Hill, NC

March 2018 – February 2019

- Lead engineer responsible for web backend (Node.js, Express), client-facing web portal (Node.js, React, Redux), and iOS / Android mobile applications (React Native, Redux, Node.js).
- Extend and implement performance improvements of backend systems to support continuing growth of the business as new clients were brought onboard and needed features added to support their unique requirements.
- Maintain and extend the functionality of the client-facing web portal used by Physicians by adding new dashboards, improving UI design and overall performance.
- Implemented Redux state management in client-facing web portal and mobile applications to handle increasingly complex state management in a predictable, consistent, centralized manner.
- Built and implemented component, module, and integration tests utilizing Jest.
- Responsible for regular monthly production releases of web backend, web portal and mobile applications through Google Play Store and Apple App Store.

Software Engineer (Remote)

IT21 Solutions, LLC, Overland Park, KS

March 2016 – September 2017

- Senior developer for MedTek21 pharmacogenetic product team. Web API, Website, and Web Job development using C#, HTML, Angular, JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS, and SASS.
- Develop MedTek21 mobile application utilizing Xamarin.Android.
- Maintain and extend functionality for client-facing systems using ASP.NET, Web API, OData, HL7, and SPA frameworks.

Software Engineer

Database Marketing Technologies, Belton, MO

December 2006 – March 2016

- Project lead and architect for frontend and backend merge systems.
- Web application development utilizing HTML, CSS, SASS, SCSS, vanilla JavaScript and JSON.
- Database architect / administrator for in-house PostgreSQL and MySQL installations.
- Evaluated, recommended, and implemented various development tools, including JavaScript frameworks, and developed company-wide coding standards and best practices.

Education

Western Governor's University BS Information Technology – Software Salt Lake City, UT Graduated May 2018

Interests

Continuous Learning Tech Blogs / Articles Harley Davidson Motorcycles